{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following disinfectant is effective against viruses?", "opta": "Hydrogen peroxide", "optb": "Hypochlorite", "optc": "Formaldehyde", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Viruses largely lack metabolic machinery of their own to generate energy or to synthesize", "opta": "protein", "optb": "carbohydrate", "optc": "alcohol", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Viruses require __________ for growth.", "opta": "bacteria", "optb": "plants", "optc": "animals", "optd": "living cells", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Reverse transcriptase is a useful enzyme to have when", "opta": "an RNA virus converts its RNA to DNA", "optb": "there are no host cells present", "optc": "nutrients are scarce", "optd": "spikes are forming in the new virus", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sequence of nucleic acid in a variety of viruses and viral host, will find more similarities", "opta": "among different viruses than between viruses and their hosts", "optb": "among different viral hosts than among different viruses", "optc": "among different viral hosts than between viruses and their hosts", "optd": "between viruses and their hosts than among different viruses", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a virus enters a cell but does not replicate immediately, the situation is called", "opta": "lysogeny", "optb": "fermentation", "optc": "symbiosis", "optd": "synergism", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Usually viruses are separated into several large groups based primarily on", "opta": "nature of the host", "optb": "nucleic acid characteristics", "optc": "capsid symmetry", "optd": "diameter of the viroin or nucleocapsid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first step in infection of a host bacterial cells by a phage is", "opta": "adsorption", "optb": "absorption", "optc": "penetration", "optd": "replication", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following viruses has not been associated with human cancer?", "opta": "Hepatitis C virus", "optb": "Hepatitis B virus", "optc": "Varicella-Zoster virus", "optd": "Herpes simplex virus type 2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The viral nucleocapsid is the combination of", "opta": "genome and capsid", "optb": "capsid and spikes", "optc": "envelope and capsid", "optd": "capsomere and genome", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Edward Jenner began inoculating humans with material from __________ lesions.", "opta": "Smallpox", "optb": "Avianpox", "optc": "Cowpox", "optd": "Chickenpox", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The viruses in an attenuated vaccine", "opta": "have no genome", "optb": "continue to replicate", "optc": "are usually larger than bacteria", "optd": "is altered with chemicals", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enveloped viruses have a __________ shape.", "opta": "icosahedral", "optb": "helical", "optc": "roughly spherical", "optd": "complex", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The envelope of which of the following viruses is derived from the host cell nucleus?", "opta": "Paramyxoviruses", "optb": "Retroviruses", "optc": "Orthomyxoviruses", "optd": "Herpesviruses", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is semi-continuous (diploid) cell line?", "opta": "HeLa", "optb": "HEp-2", "optc": "WI-38", "optd": "KB", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plant viruses may be cultivated in", "opta": "tissue culture", "optb": "cultures of separated cells", "optc": "whole plants", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The oncogene theory refers to", "opta": "how chemicals inactivate viruses when applied", "optb": "how viruses replicate in host cells", "optc": "how viruses transform normal cells into tumor cells", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In cell culture, measles virus may lead to", "opta": "nuclear pyknosis", "optb": "transformation of cells", "optc": "syncytium formation", "optd": "rounding and aggregation of cells", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A change from lysogeny to lysis is generally induced by", "opta": "ultraviolet light", "optb": "chemicals", "optc": "irradiation", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The viral DNA is removed from the host's chromosomes and the lytic cycle occurs. The process is called", "opta": "spontaneous induction", "optb": "inductive infection", "optc": "resultant induction", "optd": "spontaneous infection", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The lysogenic state is governed by the activity of the regulatory region of the lambda phage genomes; this region is termed as", "opta": "immunity repressor", "optb": "immunity operon", "optc": "operon repressor", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The capsomeres consist of a number of proteins subunits or molecules called", "opta": "protomers", "optb": "caproprotein", "optc": "procapsid", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In order for a virus to replicate", "opta": "the capsid must enter the host cell cytoplasm", "optb": "the host cell must be undergoing mitosis", "optc": "the genome must be released in the cytoplasm", "optd": "the host cell must lack a cell membrane", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following viruses belong to family Flaviviridae?", "opta": "Rubella virus", "optb": "Yellow fever virus", "optc": "Hepatitis C virus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following viruses show/s transformation of infected cells?", "opta": "Hepatitis B virus", "optb": "Human T cell lymphotronic virus type I", "optc": "Epstein-Barr virus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following may affect proteins and nucleic acids, but not viruses?", "opta": "Denaturation", "optb": "Enzyme treatment", "optc": "Pressure", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The viral DNA of the temperate phage, instead of taking over the functions of the cell's genes, is incorporated into the host DNA and becomes a prophage in the bacterial chromosome, acting as a gene. This happens in", "opta": "lysogeny", "optb": "spontaneous induction", "optc": "lytic phase", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is not true of viruses?", "opta": "Viruses have been successfully grown in pure cultures in test tubes", "optb": "All viruses are obligatory intracellular parasites", "optc": "All viruses have either DNA or RNA as their genetic material", "optd": "Viruses probably arose from small fragments of cellular chromosomes", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following viruses belong/s to family caliciviridae?", "opta": "Hepatitis B virus", "optb": "Hepatitis D virus", "optc": "Hepatitis E virus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the simplest capsid, there is a capsomere at each of the 12 vertices; this capsomere, which is surrounded by five other capsomeres, is termed a", "opta": "penton", "optb": "polyhedra", "optc": "icosahedral", "optd": "helical", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The size of viruses is usually measured in", "opta": "centimeters", "optb": "micrometers", "optc": "nanometers", "optd": "millimeters", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The temperate phage that have no site specificity for insertion and may even be able to insert multiple copies of their DNA into a single bacterial chromosome is", "opta": "\u03bb phage enzyme", "optb": "\u03bb DNA", "optc": "Phage Mu", "optd": "Phage Mn", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enzyme neuraminidase is carried by which of the following viruses?", "opta": "Human immunodeficiency virus", "optb": "Epstein-Barr virus", "optc": "Influenza virus", "optd": "Adenovirus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lysozyme (an endolysin) which will lyse the bacterial cell, releasing the mature virions is present in", "opta": "immediate early phage genes", "optb": "late genes", "optc": "delayed early genes", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is continuous cell line?", "opta": "HeLa", "optb": "HEp-2", "optc": "KB", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The repressor protein, since the cell is resistant to lysis from externally infecting phage, is also called", "opta": "immunity repressor", "optb": "immunity operon", "optc": "operon repressor", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following virus is susceptible to chloroform?", "opta": "Herpes", "optb": "Influenza", "optc": "Measles", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Group E phages have", "opta": "single stranded DNA", "optb": "double stranded DNA", "optc": "single stranded RNA", "optd": "double stranded DNA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The temperate phage possesses a gene that codes for a repressor protein which makes the cell resistant to lysis initiated by", "opta": "the prophage", "optb": "lytic infection by other viruses", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacterial viruses having head made up of large capsomeres, but no tail is morphologically classified as", "opta": "A", "optb": "B", "optc": "C", "optd": "D", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}